<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mathematics on Inderjit Singh Chahal</title><link>https://inderjit.in/tags/mathematics/</link><description>Recent content in mathematics on Inderjit Singh Chahal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</managingEditor><webMaster>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:00:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inderjit.in/tags/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Expanding Bernauli's Theorm to Real World - Amazon Reviews</title><link>https://inderjit.in/post/amazon_review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/post/amazon_review/</guid><description>Setting the objective In this blog we will try and explore the implementation of the Bernauli&amp;rsquo;s Theorm beyond the classical cases and try to get some useful information out of one of the implementation for a real world situation.
This blog will be part 1 of a two Part series where we explore bernauli&amp;rsquo;s theorm to get hold of probability of getting a positive experience after buying a product online given that there are number of sellers available and all of them have similar positive reviews based on different number of total reviews for the same product.</description></item><item><title>How I finally understood Bayes Theorem</title><link>https://inderjit.in/post/2020-10-02-first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 11:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/post/2020-10-02-first-post/</guid><description>I came across Bayesian theorem a lot early in my education carrier, much like Thomas Bayes himself, I was not able to grasp the importance of this masterpiece. Additionally, much like most of the concepts at the time I just jumped over the understanding of the same and was mostly focused on solving some predefined pattern questions and never bothered to figure out how the theorem can actually be put to use in the real-world implementations.</description></item><item><title>Stochastic Process Part 1 - Introduction to Stochastic Processes</title><link>https://inderjit.in/post/stochastic-process-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/post/stochastic-process-1/</guid><description>In this part 1, we will look at getting a better understanding of a stochastic process, in the next one we will look at some practical implementations to build on this understanding to solve some real-world problems.
What is a Stochastic Process Wikipedia defines a stochastic process as a mathematical object that is defined by a family of random variables.
A better way to look at it would be
It is a collection of random “events”, each happening with either fixed or varying probabilities, over a given time</description></item></channel></rss>