<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mathematics on Inderjit Singh Chahal</title><link>https://chahalinder0007.github.io/tags/mathematics/</link><description>Recent content in Mathematics on Inderjit Singh Chahal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>chahalinder0007.gmail.com (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</managingEditor><webMaster>chahalinder0007.gmail.com (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 11:00:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chahalinder0007.github.io/tags/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I finally understood Bayes Theorem</title><link>https://chahalinder0007.github.io/post/2020-10-02-first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 11:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>chahalinder0007.gmail.com (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://chahalinder0007.github.io/post/2020-10-02-first-post/</guid><description>I came across Bayesian theorem a lot early in my education carrier, much like Thomas Bayes himself, I was not able to grasp the importance of this masterpiece. Additionally, much like most of the concepts at the time I just jumped over the understanding of the same and was mostly focused on solving some predefined pattern questions and never bothered to figure out how the theorem can actually be put to use in the real-world implementations.</description></item><item><title>Mathematics for solving game of shells</title><link>https://chahalinder0007.github.io/post/2020-09-19-first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>chahalinder0007.gmail.com (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://chahalinder0007.github.io/post/2020-09-19-first-post/</guid><description>Simple applied mathematics for logical decisions in-game of shells or stocks maybe I shared this post that takes a simple example of Geometric progression and shows how you can quantize and make logical decisions in a game of shells, essentially betting on the outcome to be always profitable.
There was a lot of backlash from people saying its wrong to use mathematics to make money and whatnot. My point simply is, if people are aware they can have a look at mathematics in a different light and can adopt it in general life to make informed decisions.</description></item></channel></rss>