<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Inderjit Singh Chahal</title><link>https://inderjit.in/</link><description>Recent content on Inderjit Singh Chahal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</managingEditor><webMaster>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 11:00:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inderjit.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pattern Exploiting Training for NLP</title><link>https://inderjit.in/post/pet_for_nlp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 11:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/post/pet_for_nlp/</guid><description>GPT-3 created quite a buzz when it was first launched a couple of months back for its ability to generate great good amount of text to create a more realistic feel, but it suffered from one particular shortcoming that its simply too big. There has been an increasing move towards creating more light weight implementations in NLP,CV and othe areas for machine learning and artificial intelligence, evident from the fact that most of the papers now along with accuracy also feature inference times for the respective model, a good sign of end use awareness in research.</description></item><item><title>How I finally understood Bayes Theorem</title><link>https://inderjit.in/post/2020-10-02-first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 11:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/post/2020-10-02-first-post/</guid><description>I came across Bayesian theorem a lot early in my education carrier, much like Thomas Bayes himself, I was not able to grasp the importance of this masterpiece. Additionally, much like most of the concepts at the time I just jumped over the understanding of the same and was mostly focused on solving some predefined pattern questions and never bothered to figure out how the theorem can actually be put to use in the real-world implementations.</description></item><item><title>Recommender System made easier with TFRS</title><link>https://inderjit.in/post/2020-09-29-first-post.md/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 11:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/post/2020-09-29-first-post.md/</guid><description>Creating scalable deep learning-based recommendation systems from scratch is a significantly time-consuming task, especially so that we need to spend significant time on the non-productive elements involved in setting up the model for experiments. It is a given that we will need to perform levels of iterations on the model architecture to get optimal hyperparameters for a particular use case.
Google has now launched just the instrument required to reduce the non-productive component in that cycle.</description></item><item><title>Mathematics for solving game of shells</title><link>https://inderjit.in/post/2020-09-19-first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:00:01 +0530</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/post/2020-09-19-first-post/</guid><description>Simple applied mathematics for logical decisions in-game of shells or stocks maybe I shared this post that takes a simple example of Geometric progression and shows how you can quantize and make logical decisions in a game of shells, essentially betting on the outcome to be always profitable.
There was a lot of backlash from people saying its wrong to use mathematics to make money and whatnot. My point simply is, if people are aware they can have a look at mathematics in a different light and can adopt it in general life to make informed decisions.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://inderjit.in/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/page/about/</guid><description>My name is Inderjit Singh Chahal.
I enjoy working on challenging things that are new different and rare in their implementation. I like to spend hours optimizing codes or solving complex problems through simple implementations.
I enjoy debugging complex challenges in codes, like to contribute on community platforms like StackOverflow, Reddit, etc.
In my free time I like to work with financial markets, with automated strategies augmented by artificial intelligence.</description></item><item><title>Demo</title><link>https://inderjit.in/page/demo-text/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/page/demo-text/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Feedback and Testimonials</title><link>https://inderjit.in/page/feedback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/page/feedback/</guid><description>Feedback</description></item><item><title>Portfolio</title><link>https://inderjit.in/page/portfolio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>inder@inderjit.in (Inderjit Singh Chahal)</author><guid>https://inderjit.in/page/portfolio/</guid><description>Projects
What I have created so far Echo Cardiogram
Autonomous - E2E Deep-learning
A ROBOTIC INTELLIGENT RADIOLOGIST ......
A fully automated device to test and quantify the functions of a radiologist using state of the art Artificial intelligence and mathematical tools to give near human and under some circumstances, better than human results
ATM surveillance with suspicious object detectio (OCR)
The project was a ......
complete package to monitor and secure Automated teller machiens(ATMs) which was implemented using tensorflow, keras, opencv, Prometheus, grafana, web-sockets etc.</description></item></channel></rss>